A Guide to the James J. Avitabile Papers, 1963-2001
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
James J. Avitabile Papers, 1963-2001
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-057
14.0 cu. ft. 27 boxes; 2 oversize folders
Avitabile, James J.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
James J. Avitabile, an air force officer from East Haven, Connecticut, graduated from the University of Connecticut and obtained an MBA from Western New England College. He entered the United States Air Force in 1959. During his career, Lieutenant Colonel Avitabile served as an Atlas E operations launch officer and as an astronaut mission operations instructor at NASA's spacecraft simulator complex responsible for astronaut mission flight training at Cape Canaveral/Kennedy from 1965 to 1967. He also served in the Air Force's Manned Orbiting Laboratory (MOL) Program Office; as airborne test director for the E-3A Airborne Warnings and Control Systems (AWACS) Aircraft; and as activation director for the AWACS Operating Base. He was a member of the Cadre Office at NATO, responsible for the fielding of the NATO AWACS system and was a program director responsible for the acquisition of Air Force Command and Control Systems. Upon retiring from the Air Force, Lt. Col. Avitabile worked for General Electric, where he directed military and commercial space programs. Lt. Col. Avitabile and his wife Maria have three daughters and eight grandchildren.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains materials related to the Mercury, Gemini and Apollo space exploration programs of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA). Containing mostly technical data on spacecraft systems design and operation, the collection provides a detailed look at NASA systems engineering during the early to mid 1960s. The collection is divided among the following series: NASA Programs, NASA Computer Systems, NASA Public Information, and General Materials.
The NASA Programs series contains in-house technical publications detailing spacecraft systems design and procedures and is divided among three subseries. The Project Mercury subseries contains one technical report and an historical overview of the program. Much more extensive is the Project Gemini subseries, which includes such items as operations handbooks, systems diagrams, briefing outlines, reports and mission simulator manuals. The Project Apollo series also contains such materials, in addition to spacecraft manuals, study guides and charts. Together, these subseries chronicle the development and evolution of spacecraft systems design and procedures which culminated in the first lunar landing.
The NASA Computer Systems series includes programmer manuals for the various computer systems used by NASA during the Mercury, Gemini and Apollo programs. The majority of the materials in this series concern the DDP general computer system.
Unlike the Programs and Computer Systems series, the NASA Public Information series consists of materials which were produced for public education. The series contains NASA Fact Sheets and NASA Educational Briefs, other general public information booklets, a symposium report and a set of astronaut photo portraits, all produced to familiarize the public with NASA's activities, personnel and facilities.
The General Materials series contains materials related to space exploration but not produced by NASA. The series includes magazine articles and a "Sounds of Space" recording.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged according to subject matter.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Transfers
The following items were transferred to the Rare Book Collection:
Kinney, William A., Medical science and space travel (New York: F. Watts, [1959]).
Kluger, Jeffrey, The Apollo adventure: the making of the Apollo Space Program and the movie Apollo 13 (New York: Pocket Books, 1995).
Ley, Willy, et al., The complete book of satellites and outer space (New York: Maco, 1957).
Mallan, Lloyd, Secrets of space flight (Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1956).
Mallan, Lloyd, Space satellites (Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1958).
Mehrens, Harold E., The dawning space age (Ellington Air Force Base, Texas: Civil Air Patrol, 1963).
Space... the new frontier (Washington, D. C.: National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1964).
Von Braun, Wernher, Conquest of the moon (New York: Viking Press, 1953).
Index Terms
Persons:
Avitabile, James J.
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Science and Technology; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration
Occupations:
United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration--Officials and employees.
Contents List
- NASA PROGRAMS: PROJECT MERCURY, 1963, n.d.
  - Afterbody Heat Transfer Measurements Obtained During Reentry of the Spacecraft of the Mercury-Atlas 5 Mission, 1963 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Mercury Technical History, (2 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 1-2)
- NASA PROGRAMS: PROJECT GEMINI, 1963-66, n.d.
  - Project Gemini Familiarization Manual for Spacecraft #1, July 18, 1963 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Gemini Spacecraft 3 - general materials, 1964-65, n.d. (Box-folder 1-4)
    Scope and Contents note
    Systems diagrams, 1964-65 (see also Oversize Materials); Instrument panel diagram, n.d.
  - Gemini Spacecraft 4 - general materials, April 7, 1965, n.d. (Box-folder 1-5)
    BIA-SEQ. (GLV Interface), Apr. 7, 1965 (see Oversize Materials); Instrument Panel Diagram, n.d.
  - Gemini Spacecraft 5 - general materials, 1965 (Box-folder 1-6)
    Instrument panel diagram, Feb. 3, 1965; Launch Vehicle Guidance and Control Subsystem diagram, Jun. 25, 1965; Fuel Cell Power System Briefing, 1965
  - Gemini Spacecraft 6 Operations Handbook, 1965 (Box-folder 1-7 to 1-9)
    Section I - Systems, [1965] (3 folders)
    Section II - Controls and Displays, Sept. 10, 1965 (2 folders)
    Section II - Controls and Displays (Revision B), Nov. 24, 1965
  - Gemini Spacecraft 6 Operations Handbook, 1965 (Box-folder 2-1 to 2-2)
    Section III - Spacecraft Operations Procedures, Oct. 3, 1965
    Section III - Spacecraft operations Procedures (Revision B), Nov. 26, 1965
  - Gemini Spacecraft 6 - Flight Data, n.d. (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Gemini Spacecraft 7 - general materials, 1965-66 (Box-folder 2-4)
    Instrument panel diagram, Apr. 16, 1965
    Fuel Cell Power System Briefing, Nov. 9, 1965
    Reactant Supply System Fuel Cell Performance Analysis, Mar. 9, 1966
  - Gemini Agenda Operations Handbook - Vehicle 5003 [Gemini VIII], (2 folders), Jan. 21, 1966 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Gemini VIII - General materials, 1965-66 (Box-folder 2-6)
    Mission Profile, Jan. 20, 1966
    Normal Phase Pane Detail, Jan. 25, 1965
    Launch Windows, Jan. 25, 1966
    Instrument panel diagram, Feb. 11, 1966
    Astronaut Briefing: Communication Systems, Apr. 6, 1966
    Rendezvous procedures, [1966]
  - Gemini-Titan 9 Cape Gemini Mission Simulator Configuration, 1966 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Gemini IX, 1966 (Box-folder 2-8 to 2-10)
    Orbital and Rendezvous Report, Apr. 14, 1966
    Preflight Reentry Report, Apr. 14, 1966
    Flight Plan, Apr. 18, 1966 (2 folders)
  - Gemini IX, 1966 (Box-folder 3-1 to 3-4)
    Operations Handbook (Revision C), May 20, 1966 (3 folders)
    Mission Rules (Revision G), May 25, 1966 (3 folders)
    Mission Plan/Preliminary Trajectory Plan, [1966]
    General Materials
    Preliminary Mission Profile [cover and title pg. only], Jan. 18, 1966
    Astronaut Briefing: Propulsion, Apr. 7, 1966
    Spacecraft 9 Power System Review, [1966]
    Bus power diagram, [1966]
    Command Pilot Rendezvous Book, [1966]
    Instrument panel diagram, [1966]
    Astronaut Briefing: Environmental Control System, [1966]
  - Gemini IX-A Flight Plan, (2 folders), May 21, 1966 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Gemini X Operations Handbook, 1966 (Box-folder 4-1 to 4-2)
    Section II (Preliminary) - Controls and Displays, May 20, 1966 (3 folders)
    Section III - Spacecraft Operations Procedures, May 10, 1966 (2 folders)
  - Gemini X - general materials, 1966 (Box-folder 4-3)
    Instrument panel diagram, May 20, 1966
    >Non-Nominal Reset Points, Jun. 9, 1966
    Launch/Reentry Exercises, Jun. 13, 1966
    Gemini-Titan X/SNS/01, Jun. 13, 1966
    Gemini-Titan X/SNS/02, [1966]
    Gemini-Titan X/SNS/04, [1966]
  - Gemini XI - proposed procedures, 1966 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Gemini XII - Cape Gemini Mission Simulator Configuration, Nov. 22, 1966 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - Gemini systems, 1963 (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Operations Manual for Gemini Mission Simulator (3 folders), Dec. 18, 1963 (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Gemini Mission Simulator Fault Summary (2 folders), Jan. 6, 1964 (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Gemini Mission Simulator Software Support, Aug. 1964 (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Gemini Launch Data System Data Book, Jan. 22, 1965 (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Gemini Overall Operations Countdown: Gemini Missions, Feb. 7, 1966 (Box-folder 5-4)
  - Augmented Target Docking Adaptor - Performance/Configuration Specification [Gemini Program] (Revised), Apr. 7, 1966 (Box-folder 5-5)
  - Project Gemini Familiarization Manual [v.2]: Rendezvous and Docking Configurations (3 folders), Aug. 22, 1966 (Box-folder 5-6)
  - Project Gemini - general materials (see also Oversize Materials), 1965-66, n.d. (Box-folder 6-1)
- NASA PROGRAMS: PROJECT APOLLO, 1964-67, n.d.
  - AS-202 Operational Spacecraft Flight Trajectory, Jul. 18, 1966 (Box-folder 6-2)
  - Apollo Mission Simulator: Instructor Handbook - Spacecraft 012 [AS-204A]/v. 1 - Description and Utilization, (5 folders)(see also Oversize Materials), Apr. 15, 1966 (Box-folder 6-3)
  - Apollo Mission Simulator: Instructor Handbook - Spacecraft 012 [AS-204A]/v. 2 - Instructor Workbook, (10 folders), Apr. 15, 1966 (Box-folder 7-1)
  - Crew Abbreviated Checklist - AS-204A, Apr. 15, 1966 (Box-folder 7-2)
  - Command Service Module System Handbook: AS-204 (Revision A), (3 folders), Aug. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 8-1)
  - Apollo AS-204A Flight Plan (Preliminary), Sept. 6, 1966 (Box-folder 8-2)
  - Mission Rules - AS 204A Flight Plan (Preliminary), (2 folders), Sept. 9, 1966 (Box-folder 8-3)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook: 204 A, Sept. 16, 1966 (Box-folder 8-4)
  - Saturn Launch Vehicle AS-204 (Revision A), (3 folders), Oct. 21, 1966 (Box-folder 8-5)
  - Flight Crew Launch Abort Mode Selection Charts for Mission AS-204A, Oct. 21, 1966 (Box-folder 9-1)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook: Command Service Module Spacecraft 012 - AS204A, [fragments], Apr. 15, 1966 (Box-folder 9-2)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook: Command Service Module Spacecraft 012, (5 folders), Nov. 12, 1966 (Box-folder 9-3)
  - Command Service Module Spacecraft 012 Subsystem - Operating Logic Schematics, (2 folders), 1966 (Box-folder 9-4)
  - Apollo II Astronaut/Command Module Computer Logic, 1967 (Box-folder 9-5)
  - Command Service Module System Handbook AS-501, (3 folders), Jan. 16, 1967 (Box-folder 10-1)
  - Mission Rules: 204 LM-1 (Preliminary), (2 folders), May 22, 1967 (Box-folder 10-2)
  - Lunar Module Systems Handbook: AS-204/LM-1, 1967 (Box-folder 10-3 to 10-4)
    (Revision C), Jul. 7, 1967 (2 folders)
    (Revision C - Reprint), Aug. 2, 1967 (2 folders)
  - Apollo Guidance Navigation and Control: Guidance System Operations Plan LM-1 Using Burst Program, (2 folders), Jul. 1967 (Box-folder 11-1)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook: Command Service Module Spacecraft 014 [AS-205] - Spacecraft and Systems Description (v.1), (4 folders), Oct. 17, 1966 (Box-folder 11-2)
  - Saturn Launch Vehicle AS-205, (3 folders), Oct. 25, 1966 (Box-folder 11-3)
  - Flight Crew Abbreviated Checklist: Mission AS-205/208 Apollo Spacecraft 101, Feb. 13, 1967 (Box-folder 12-1)
  - Crew Abbreviated Checklist: Mission AS-205/208A Apollo Spacecraft 101, (2 folders), Mar. 1, 1967 (Box-folder 12-2)
  - AS 205/208 - general materials, 1967 (Box-folder 12-3)
    Command Service Module Systems Handbook: Command Service Modules 101 - Publication and Control Sheet, Apr. 28, 1967
    Apollo Guidance and Navigation - [AS-205/208], Jun. 1967
    >Apollo Orbital Charts and Procedures - [AS 205/208],[1967]
  - Lunar Module Systems Handbook Vehicle LM-1: AS-206, 1966-67 (Box-folder 12-4 to 12-5)
    (Revision A), Oct. 27, 1966 (3 folders)
    (Revision B), Mar. 16, 1967 (3 folders)
  - Lunar Module Systems Handbook Vehicle LM-1: AS-206 (Revision B - Replacement Pages), Apr. 21, 1967 (Box-folder 13-1)
  - Lunar Module Abort Guidance System - AS-207/208 (Revision B - Preliminary), (2 folders), Jan. 4, 1967 (Box-folder 13-2)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook - LEM2 Subsystems Data [AS-207/208A],Sept. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 13-3)
  - AS-278A Astronaut/Lunar Module Guidance Computer Logic [AS-207/208A], (2 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 13-4)
  - Electrical Power Subsystem, Electroexplosive Devices, and Lighting System Briefing, 1967 (Box-folder 13-5)
  - Environmental Control System Briefing (Revised)[AS-207/208A], Aug. 29, 1967 (Box-folder 13-6)
  - Reaction Control System and Propulsion System Briefing [AS-207/208A], 1967 (Box-folder 13-7)
  - Saturn IB Orientation Course, (4 folders), c.1964 (Box-folder 13-8)
  - Lunar Excursion Module Familiarization Manual, (2 folders), Oct. 15, 1965 (Box-folder 14-1)
  - Lunar Excursion Module Guidance and Control Data Book (Revision 1 - Change A), (4 folders), Dec. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 14-2)
  - Lunar Module Guidance and Control Data Book (Revision 2), (3 folders), Jul. 15, 1967 (Box-folder 14-3)
  - Lunar Module Abbreviation List, (3 folders), 1967 (Box-folder 15-1)
  - Lunar Module Orientation (Revised), Nov. 1966 (Box-folder 15-2)
  - Lunar Module Study Guide, 1967 (Box-folder 15-3 to 15-6)
    Communications Subsystem (Revision C), Jan. 1967
    Control Electronics Section and Abort Guidance Section, Feb. 1967 (2 folders)
    Crew Systems, Feb. 1967 (3 folders)
    Electrical Power Subsystem, Jan. 1, 1967
  - Lunar Module Study Guide, 1966 (Box-folder 16-1 to 16-3)
    Environmental Control Subsystem (Revised), Dec. 1966 (2 folders)
    Guidance, Navigation and Control Subsystem, Mar. 1, 1966 (2 folders)
    Instrumentation Subsystem (Revised), Nov. 1966 (3 folders)
  - Lunar Module Study Guide, Feb. 1967 (Box-folder 16-4 to 16-5)
    Propulsion and Reaction Control System, Feb. 1967 (2 folders)
    Radars, Feb. 1967 (2 folders)
  - Lunar Module Study Guide, Feb. 15, 1967 (Box-folder 17-1)
    Structures, Mechanical Systems and Electroexplosive Devices, (2 folders)
  - Lunar Module primary Guidance and Navigation and Control System Student Study Guide, 1967 (Box-folder 17-2 to 17-4)
    Familiarization Course (Revision A), Jan. 20, 1967 (2 folders)
    System Mechanization, Jan. 27, 1967 (5 folders)
    Computer Utility Programs (Revision A), Apr. 5, 1967 (3 folders)
  - Command Module Primary Guidance and Navigation and Control System Student Study Guide, 1966 (Box-folder 18-1 to 18-2)
    Familiarization Course (Revision A), Feb. 15, 1967 (3 folders)
    Computer Utility Programs, Mar. 2, 1967 (3 folders)
  - Apollo Block II Command Service Module Guidance and Control Data Book (Revision 2), (3 folders), Sept. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 18-3)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook, 1967 (Box-folder 19-1 to 19-5)
    Block II Spacecraft (v.1 - Spacecraft Description), Mar. 1, 1967 (5 folders)
    Command Service Modules Block II (Preliminary)
    Service Propulsion System (Subsection 2.4), Mar. 1, 1967
    Environmental Control System (Subsection 2.7), Feb. 1, 1967
    Telecommunications System (Subsection 2.8), Mar. 1, 1967
    Sequential Systems (Subsection 2.9), Feb. 1, 1967
  - Command Service Module Lunar Module Docking and Crew Transfer: Block II Handout, Feb. 7, 1967 (Box-folder 19-6)
  - Apollo Training, 1967 (Box-folder 9-7 to 19-10)
    Block II Command Service Modules Propulsion Subsystem, Feb. 23, 1967
    Electrical Power Subsystem Feb. 22, 1967
    Guidance and Control Systems - Block II, Mar. 31, 1967 (2 folders)
    Telecommunications System, Feb. 15, 1967
  - Apollo Training Study Guide, 1965-66 (Box-folder 20-1 to 20-6)
    Crew Equipment, Apr. 1, 1966
    Crew Systems, Mar. 1, 1965
    Electrical Power System, Oct. 1, 1965
    Environmental Control Subsystem Feb. 18, 1966
    Guidance and Navigation Subsystem, Mar. 25, 1966
    Stabilization and Control Subsystem, May. 9, 1966
  - Lunar Module Simulator Malfunction Repertoire, Dec. 20, 1966 (Box-folder 20-7)
  - Lunar Module Mission Simulator - Instructors Handbook, Apr. 1, 1967 (Box-folder 20-8)
    v.1 - Simulator Description, (5 folders)
  - Lunar Module Mission Simulator - Instrutors Handbook, Apr. 1, 1967 (Box-folder 21-1 to 21-2)
    v.2 - Simulator Operation, Apr. 1, 1967
    Section 1 - Simulator Operation (2 folders)
    v.2 - Simulator Operation (Changed), May 15, 1967
    Section 1 - Simulator Operation
  - v.2 - Simulator Operation, Apr. 1, 1967 (Box-folder 21-3 to 21-5)
    Section 2 - Malfunction Data (3 folders)
    Section 3 - Lunar-landing Mission Procedures (4 folders)
    Section 4 - Instructor Activity for Interface Operation
  - v.2 - Simulator Operation (Changed), May 15, 1967 (Box-folder 21-6)
  - Lunar Module Mission Simulator - Instructors Handbook, 1967 (Box-folder 22-1 to 22-3)
    Section 5 - Instructor Material (6 folders)
    Section 6 - Scripting Data Sheets (2 folders)
    Section 7 - Simulator Output Tables, Jul. 1, 1967 (3 folders)
  - Apollo Operations Handbook: Lunar Module 2, 1967 (Box-folder 23-1 to 23-3)
    v.1, Jan 1, 1967 (3 folders)
    v.2, Jan. 1, 1967 (3 folders)
    v.2, (Changed), Mar. 20, 1967
  - JL4-2 Earth Orbital Checkout Procedures - Lunar Module 2, Mar. 1, 1967 (Box-folder 23-4)
  - Visual Simulation Equipment Study, Mar. 24, 1965 (Box-folder 23-5)
  - Student Training Guide: Toxic Propellants and Gas Mask Certification, Apr. 9, 1966 (Box-folder 23-6)
  - Description of Test Reset Points [for lunar landing], 1966 (Box-folder 23-7)
  - Air Force Eastern Test Range Instrumentation Familiarization Course - RCA Technical Training, Apr. 1967 (Box-folder 23-8)
  - Apollo Astronaut/Lunar Module Guidance Computer Logic, May, 1967 (Box-folder 24-1)
  - Student Training Guides, 1967 (Box-folder 24-2)
    Complex 34/37 Safety Orientation - Course OP-108, Aug. 15, 1967
    Complex 39 Safety Orientation - Course OP-107, Aug. 1, 1967
  - Briefing Outlines, 1967, n.d. (Box-folder 24-3)
    Rendezvous Radar/Transportation System, [1967]
    Control Electronics Section System, n.d.
    Instrumentation Subsystem, n.d.
  - Charts and calculators, (see also Oversize Materials), 1967, n.d. (Box-folder 24-4)
  - Apollo training - general materials, (2 folders), 1966-67, n.d. (Box-folder 24-5)
- NASA COMPUTER SYSTEMS, 1962-66, n.d.
  - Mark I Programmer's Manual, (3 folders), 1962 (Box-folder 25-1)
  - Preliminary Instruction Manual for H-PAC Digital Modules, (2 folders), Mar. 1, 1963 (Box-folder 25-2)
  - Preliminary DDP-24 Installation Instruction Manual, Oct. 1963 (Box-folder 25-3)
  - Preliminary DIP Interpretive program for the DDP-24 General Purpose Computer, 1963 (Box-folder 25-4)
  - Preliminary Programmer's Manual for the DDP General Purpose Computer (Revised), Feb. 1964 (Box-folder 25-5)
  - DAP Manual for the DDP-24 General Purpose Computer, Mar. 1964 (Box-folder 25-6)
  - Instruction Manual - DDP-24 General Purpose Computer, (4 folders), Apr. 1, 1964 (Box-folder 25-7)
  - Installation and Interface Manual for DDP-24 General Purpose Computer, May, 1965 (Box-folder 25-8)
  - Programmers Manual - DDP-24 General Purpose Computer, Aug. 1965 (Box-folder 26-1)
  - Fortran IV for DDP Computers, 1965 (Box-folder 26-2)
  - DAP II Manual - DDP General Purpose Computers, Apr. 1966 (Box-folder 26-3)
  - DDP-24 General Purpose Digital Computer, n.d. (Box-folder 26-4)
  - Powercel 3A-2 Installation and Operation Handbook, Apr. 1966 (Box-folder 26-5)
  - Computer systems - general materials, (2 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 26-6)
- NASA PUBLIC INFORMATION, 1962-1991, n.d.
  - NASA Fact Sheets, [7 items], 1962-66 (Box-folder 27-1)
  - NASA Educational Briefs, [14 items], n.d. (Box-folder 27-2)
  - Apollo Lunar Landing Mission Symposium, Jun. 25-27, 1966 (Box-folder 27-3)
  - General NASA printed materials, 1963-1991, n.d. (Box-folder 27-4)
    NASA Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, Texas, [c.1963]
    NASA Manned Spacecraft Center, [1964]
    NASA Facts, v.2, no.5: Launch Vehicles, [1965]
    Roster of Military Personnel at NASA Manned Spacecraft Center, 1966
    Payload Flight Assingments - NASA Mixed Fleet, 1989-91 [2 items]
  - NASA astronaut publicity photo portraits, [44 items](2 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 27-5)
- GENERAL MATERIALS, 1969-2001, n.d.
  - General Materials, 1969-2001, n.d. (Box-folder 27-6)
    Discover Magazine, Oct. 2001 (includes article on a Russian Space program)
    IEEE Spectrum, Jul. 1994 (includes "The Moon Landing: a 25th Anniversary Perspective")
    USAA Magazine, Jun/Jul 1999 (features article on first lunar landing)
    "America in Space" - Science Applications International Calendar, 1997
    National Geographic "Sounds of Space Age" sound disc, 1969
- Oversize Materials, 1964-66
  - Gemini Spacecraft 3 - general materials (from Box 1, Folder 4), 1964-65 (Box-folder Oversize-1)
    Systems diagrams, 1964-65
    Attitude Control and Maneuver Electronics, Nov. 1, 1964
    Environmental Control - Oxygen, Nov. 9, 1964
    Electric Battery Control, Nov. 1, 1964
    Environmental Control - Coolant, Dec. 4, 1964
    Environmental Control - Life Support, Dec. 1, 1964
    Environmental Control System - Coolant Loop, Nov. 11, 1964
    Flight Directory and Attitude Display Indicators, Jan. 29, 1965
    IGS-ACC and Attitude Malfunction Detection, Jan. 22, 1965
    IGS-Clock, 400~Power and Accelerometer, Jan. 22, 1965
    IGS-Platform Control, Feb. 4, 1965
    IGS (Power and Control), Jan. 22, 1965
    Manual Data Insertion Unit, Dec. 18, 1964
    Orbit Attitude and Maneuver propulsion, Nov. 1, 1964
    Orbit Attitude and Maneuver, Jul. 21, 1964
    Re-entry Control, Nov. 1, 1964
    Retrograde Seq., Nov. 1, 1964
    Sequential - Landing and Post-landing, Nov. 1, 1964
    Time Reference, Jan. 19, 1965
    Voice Communications, Nov. 9, 1964
    Communications - Digital Command, Nov. 9, 1964
    Communications - Beacon Control, Nov. 5, 1964
    BIA-SEQ., Dec. 21, 1964
  - Gemini Spacecraft 4 - general materials (from Box 1, Folder 5), Apr. 7, 1965 (Box-folder Oversize-1)
    BIA-SEQ. (GLV Interface)
  - Project Gemini - general materials, (from Box 6, Folder 1), 1963-66, n.d. (Box-folder Oversize-2)
    Floor Plan - Cape Canaveral Gemini Mission
    Instrument panel diagrams, n.d. [2 items]
    Environmental Control System - Coolant Circuit
    Environmental Control System - Oxygen Circuit diagram, n.d.
  - Apollo Mission Simulator: Instructor Handbook - Spacecraft 012 [AS-204A]/v.1 - Description and Utilization - system diagrams, [12 items] (from Box 6, Folder 3), Apr. 15, 1966 (Box-folder Oversize-2)
  - Charts and Calculators (from Box 24, Folder 4), n.d. (Box-folder Oversize-2)
    Orbital tracking chart, n.d.
    Fuel chart, n.d.
    TSPI Systems chart, n.d.
    Film charts, n.d. [2 items]